《 透 明 人 》
òhey have this All Bird TV. You seen it?
No. - Sure, it's All Bird TV.
I'm giving them a plug.
It's all birds. I watch it with the cat, the cat, fixated by it.
“不稳定”
Damn it!
妈的！
该死
Damn it.
“你该工作”
“稳定”
我真是个天才
I am a goddamn genius.
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
赛巴斯辛，你知道现在几点吗？
Sebastian, do you have any idea what time it is?
天才从不浪费时间睡觉
Da Vinci never slept. Said it was a waste of time.
那是谁？
Who's that?
不关你的事
Not your business.
不再是了
Not anymore.
琳达…
Linda...
…我找到还原配方了
... I cracked the reversión.
你找到了？
You cracked it?
你看
Look at this.
注意看
Watch.
“稳定”
过了11个月，你就突然开窍了？ 怎么会？
Eleven months and you suddenly come up with it out of the blue? How?
老套，咖啡加点心
The usual. Coffee and Twinkies.
我恨你
I hate you.
你能找麦特一起去实验室吗？ 我要伊莎贝拉准备好活体实验
Can you find Matt and get to the lab? I want Isabelle for a live test.
我想能找到他
I think I can find him.
你何时会到？
When will you be in?
嗯，瑞典现在该是白天
Well, it should be daylight in Sweden now.
我该通知诺贝尔委员会 请他们准备好我们的奖
So I should call the Nobel committee and tell them to get our prize ready.
等会见了
I'll see you in a few.
麦特
Matt.
赛巴斯辛来电，我们得去实验室
Sebastian called. We gotta get to the lab.
急什么？
What's the rush?
他发现还原配方了
He cracked reversión.
别开玩笑了
You're kidding.
- 何时的事？ - 当我们睡觉时
When? - While we were sleeping.
我载你去吧？
You want a ride?
也许我们该各自开车去
Maybe we should take our own cars.
我不想再偷偷摸摸的了，琳
I'm tired of this sneaking around, Lin.
你总得告诉他的
You're gonna have to tell him eventually.
我会的，总有一天
I will, eventually.
我是在等待时机
I'm just waiting for the right time.
对赛巴斯辛而言 时机永远都不对
With Sebastian, there's never gonna be a right time.
但你注定死亡
因为我天生注定要飞
早安，凯恩博士
Morning, Dr. Caine. - Morning.
- 祝你顺心 - 谢谢
Have a nice day, sir. - Thank you.
- 早安 - 早安，艾德
Good morning, sir. - Morning, Ed.
你们今天很早，有特别的事吗？
Your team's in early today. Something special?
抱歉，你知道规定的
Sorry, Ed. You know the rules.
“扫瞄中”
- 授权码 - 凯恩，0027
Authorization, please. - Caine, 0027.
确认
Confirmed.
Hi.
伊莎贝拉
Isabelle.
别这样，伊莎贝拉
Come on, Isabelle.
冷静点，宝贝
Calm down, baby.
乖孩子
Good girl.
不会有事的
It's okay.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
别动
Hold still.
是伊莎贝拉？
Isabelle?
她最近变得更有侵略性了
She's more aggressive these days.
所以才要用镇静剂 我去抓她
That's what tranquillizers are for. L'll get her.
她隐形太久了 那开始影响她的大脑
She's been gone too long. It's starting to affect her brain.
- 去料理伤口吧 - 我会的
You take care of that bite. - L'll manage.
Hey.
我赌十元能先逮到她
Ten bucks says I nail her first.
成交
You're on.
Isabelle?
爸爸帮你准备了个惊喜
Got a surprise for you.
你没射中
You missed.
也许是因为我不用午餐时练习
Maybe because I don't spend my lunch hours practicing.
你欠我十元
You owe me ten.
记帐
Put it on my tab.
搞不好改天我真的会要你清帐
You know, someday I may actually make you pay up.
莎拉很愤怒，你最好友善点
Sarah's on the warpath, so you play nice.
- 这根本是乱搞，赛巴斯辛 - 你也早安
This is bullshit, Sebastian. - And good morning to you too.
把大猩猩搬上桌吧
Get the monkey on the table.
你怎能对伊莎贝拉注射 未经试验的配方液？
How can you justify injecting Isabelle with the serum without even testing it?
这样省时
Because it'll save time.
那你负责收拾善后
Then you can mop up afterwards.
你以为我想害死伊莎贝拉？
You think I'm trying to kill Isabelle?
- 害死？根本是溶解她 - 实验室准备好了
Kill? More like liquefy. - Lab's prepped.
异议收到且即刻被驳回
Well, your objections are duly noted and summarily overruled.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
为什么当你说“是的，长官”时 听来像是“去你的”
How come when you say, 'Yes, sir,' it sounds like 'Fuck you'?
练习就行
Practice.
你怎么说服我雇用她的？
How'd you convince me to hire her?
你说你要全美最棒的兽医
You wanted the best vet in the U.S.
- 她过度关心动物 - 所以她才棒啊
She cares more about the animals. - And maybe that's why she's so good.
你的约会对象长什么德性？
So this guy you're seeing, what's he like?
他跟你完全不一样
He's everything you're not.
他一定很无聊
He must be dull.
- 40秒内开始 - 好
Ready in 40. - Okay.
生命迹象？
Vitals?
全部正常
All normal.
过于滥用“正常”这二字了吧
Using the word 'normal' loosely, of course.
- 紧急医疗组待命 - 技术组，情况如何？
Emergency medical, standing by. - Tech, status?
我是上帝
This is God.
你扰乱了万物的秩序…
You are disturbing the natural order of things...
…将永世受到严厉的惩罚
... and will be severely punished for all eternity.
上帝说话了
God has spoken.
我要告诉你多少次，法兰克…
How many times must I tell you, Frank...
…你不是上帝
...you're not God.
我才是
I am.
抱歉，老大，我忘了
Sorry, chief. Forgot.
准备开始了吗？
You guys ready to roll yet?
好了
Yes.
那些狗屎医学博士好像都不用等
Like those sorry-ass M.D. S have ever had to wait for us.
告诉皇上我两小时前就好了
Tell His Highness Mary was hot two hours ago.
好，我会呈报
Yeah, l'll tell him that.
- 准备好了，老大 - 开始录影
Ready up here, chief. - Roll and record.
开始录了
Rolling.
实验对象：伊莎贝拉二号 隐形状态，已达126小时
Subject, Isabelle Two. Currently in phase-shift, 126 hours.
第四级程序…
Testing D-phase protocol...
…凯氏辐射蛋白125号
...Serial Irradiated Protein Caine 125.
不用你的名字，也许会成功
Stop naming them after yourself, you'd have better luck.
谢了，肯博士，你观察真敏锐
Thank you, Dr. Kensington, for that keen observation.
我会记在备忘录上
L'll include it in my memoirs.
我也会记你一笔
L'll make sure to put you in mine.
你们认真点好吗？
Would you guys be serious, please?
- 她熬得过来吗？ - 不知道，我只是在这工作
You think she'll make it? - I don't know, I just work here.
量子值已测定
Quantum signatures are calibrated.
莎拉，找出血管
Okay, Sarah, get us a vein.
喷雾
Spray.
血管找到了
Vein's prepped.
很好
All right.
无用的解药来了
Here goes nothing.
措词不当，马修，这是我的特权
Bad form, Matthew. The honor is mine.
Okay.
注射时间在早上8点47分…
Injection occurred at 0847.
心跳加快了
Elevated heartbeat.
- 情况还稳定 - 确认
We're still in the green. - Confirmed.
生物电流与量子状态指示器 很稳定
Bioelectric energy and quantum shift indicators are stable.
有细胞反应
We're getting cellular reaction.
有用，真的有用
It's working. It's actually working.
当然，别太自大
Of course it is. - Don't get cocky.
心跳上升，她吓到了，没事的
Heart rate's up. She's scared. It's okay.
实验对象几乎是立刻起反应 程序进行快速
Subject began manifesting immediately. Protocol's acting quickly.
“生物电流量警示”
该死，血压过低，脉搏过高
Goddamn it, blood pressure crashing. Pulse high.
她的心脏
It's her heart.
心律不整，脑波频率过高
I got erratic heartbeat and brain activity.
- 她心跳要停止了 - 电击器！
She's going into cardiac arrest. - Defib!
准备强心针
Prep an intracardiac.
- 没动静，她不行了 - 不，她不会，电击她！
Flatline. We're losing her. - No, we're not. Hit her!
站开   ！
Clear!
- 再来 - 站开
Again. - Clear.
- 再来！ - 站开
Again! - Clear.
- 快啊 - 再来！
Come on. - Again!
站开！
Clear!
该死！强心针
Fuck! Intracardiac.
等等！有动静了
Wait! No, we got something.
还是不稳定…
Still erratic...
…稳定下来了
...and stabilizing.
天啊
Oh, man.
脑波频率回复正常 量子值稳定
Brain activity returning to normal. Quantum signatures are stable.
欢迎回来，伊莎贝拉
Welcome back, Isabelle.
Yeah. Yeah!
好耶！
Yeah, baby!
- 我们成功了 - 干的好
We did it. - Good work, everyone.
好耶！就是这样干的
Yeah! That's the way it's done, man.
她还好吗？
So how's she doing, doc?
我想她不会有事的
Well, I think she's gonna be okay.
- 来吧，进去 - 来，伊莎贝拉
Come on. Right in there. - Come on, Isabelle.
去啊，好女孩
Go ahead. Good girl.
看她多温驯
Look how peaceful she is.
真像什么事都没发生过似的
It seems like nothing happened to her.
星期一安排活体解剖 检查她的神经系统
Schedule a vivisection for Monday. I wanna check her neuropathways.
才救回她就要剖开她的大脑？
You just brought her back and you're gonna slice up her brain?
我又不是开动物园的！
I'm not running a goddamn zoo!
- 你真是个卑劣的混蛋 - 快跟她说你是开玩笑的
You're a fucking unethical bastard. - Tell her you're kidding.
- 对吧？ - 对
Right? - Right.
我这个星期还不会剖开她
I won't cut her for another week.
别太过份了
Don't be such an asshole.
我们终于有东西值得庆祝了
We finally have something to celebrate.
- 酷，我饿了，走吧 - 我也是
Cool. I'm hungry, let's go. - Me too.
我们真该把你剖了
We should cut you up.
各位女士，先生们，请注意
Ladies and gentlemen, a moment of your time, please.
要来了
Here it comes.
敬最顶尖的研究团队
To the finest research team I have ever known.
干杯
Cheers.
接著发生爆炸，后来她说：
There was a big explosión, and afterward she said:
“如果你这么聪明 为何你还在念二年级？”
'If you're so smart, how come you're still in the second grade?'
- 她眉毛多久才长回来？ - 一个月
She grew her eyebrows back? - In a month.
- 你被留校察看了多久？ - 一个月
How long were you suspended? - A month.
我以为你走了
Hey, I thought you'd gone.
我没地方可去
There's nowhere to go.
我错过了什么？
Did I miss something?
你不是该快乐吗？
Aren't you supposed to be happy?
还原是最后的突破了 感觉像是个终点的开始
Reversión was the last breakthrough. Feels like the beginning of the end.
不对，我们得到了丰富的资料
That's not true. We've got a lifetime of data.
麦特这种人有耐性解读资料 但你知道我…
Matt has the patience to crunch the numbers, but you know me...
…我需要浮华世界
...I need this grandeur and the spectacle.
我无法想像自己做琐事
I can't concern myself with the details.
我知道，我是其中一个
Yeah, I know. I was one of them.
我以为我们在一起很棒
I thought we were great together.
你是很棒
You were great.
我只是陪衬你而已
I was just standing next to you.
拜托，我们有过快乐时光啊
Come on. We had some good times.
是啊，我们有过一些快乐时光
Yeah, we had some good times.
你有想回到过去吗？
Have you ever wanted to turn the clock back?
回去再试一次？
Go back and try again?
我想那种时光旅行并不存在
L'd say that kind of time travel doesn't exist.
也许我们该发明它
Well, maybe we should invent it.
或者不用
Or not.
那是什么感觉？
What's it like?
四年前，委员会给我…
Four years ago, this committee gave me...
…一个很有挑战性的任务…
...a very specific and challenging task...
…要将人同步量子化…
...to phase-shift a human being out of quantum sync...
…变为隐形状态…
...with the visible universe...
…再将他无后遗症的安全还原
...and return him safely with no aftereffects.
我们发现要让动物隐形简单
We found that sending them to never-never land was easy.
还原他们才是最难的
It's the getting them back that's hard.
DNA链会衰退？
Primary DNA strands decaying on you?
细胞链也不稳定
Along with cellular bond instability.
这些问题怎么解决？
How have you solved the problem?
我没解决
I haven't.
但很接近了
But we're close.
我们还需要些时间
We just need more time.
从你大一走进教室那一刻起…
Ever since you walked in my class your freshman year...
…我就知道你与众不同
...I knew you were different.
这些年，你的表现更令人激赏
Over the years, your genius has been most impressive.
谢谢，克拉玛博士
Thank you, Dr. Kramer.
先别谢我
Well, don't thank me yet.
本委员会给了你很特别的自由空间
This committee has given you remarkable leeway.
我们忍耐了你的怪僻 以及让你保有隐私权的需要
We've tolerated your eccentricities, as well as your need for privacy.
而我向你保证 我们的耐性已耗尽
And I assure you, our patience is running out.
如果你不能尽快提出成果…
If we don't get results and get them soon...
…你就再也不能让我激赏了
...your genius will cease to impress me.
如果你无法成功…
And if you can't make it work...
…我也会找到另一个 赛巴斯辛来完成
...l'll find another Sebastian Caine who can.
- 到底怎么回事？ - 你最好有好理由
What just happened in there? - This better be good.
- 我还不想让他们知道 - 你还不想？
I wasn't ready for them to know. - You weren't ready?
想不想不是问题 你有了结果就该跟他们报告
Being ready's not it. You have results, you report them.
- 我能解释吗？ - 你欺骗了五角大厦！
Can I explain? - You just lied to the Pentagon!
一旦他们知道我们成功了…
Once they know we've completed it...
…有什么可以阻止 他们接手整个计划？
...what's to stop them from taking over the project?
- 为什么他们要这么做？ - 因为他们不需要我们了
Why would they? - Because they won't need us.
但这是他们的计划啊 总有一天会发生的
But it's their project. It's gonna happen sometime.
那也许是他们的计划 但这是我的梦想，我的远景
It may be their project, but it's my dream, my visión.
- 你在建议什么？ - 直接进行第三阶段实验
What are you proposing? - That we go to Phase Three ourselves.
第三阶段实验？你疯了？
Phase Three? Are you nuts?
你不能直接做人体实验 要依循法令和程序
You can't jump into human testing. There's rules, procedures.
循规蹈矩不能创造历史 把握机会才能
You don't make history with rules. You make it by seizing the moment.
你想做第一个，就是这样
You wanna be the first one. That's what this is about.
这不是为我，是为了我们 我们说过要改变世界
This is not about me, it's about us. We said we would change the worid.
机会就在眼前
Now is our chance.
我们会赢得诺贝尔奖的.
And we'll get the Nobel Prize.
来吧，伙计.
Come on, buddy.
你知道，要是有人发现我们欺骗了他们...
You know, if somebody finds out that we bypassed advisory review...
- 我们就丢饭碗了. - 但如果我们成功了,没人会在乎.
...we're never gonna work again. - But if it works, no one'll care.
你怎么得到第三阶段实验许可？
How did you get clearance for Phase Three?
- 我自愿，他们批准了 - 不可能
I volunteered. They approved. - No way.
你开玩笑
You're kidding.
你自愿？你疯了？
You volunteered? Are you insane?
沙克就在自己身上试验疫苗 他也疯了？
Jonas Salk tested the polio vaccine on himself. Was he insane?
是的，我相信他是
Yeah, I'm pretty sure he was.
妈的
Shit.
过去四周来，我们成功的 还原七只猿猴
In the past four weeks, we have brought back seven primates.
- 我想结果很清楚 - 只有你自己相信吧？
The results speak for themselves. - Or do you wanna believe that?
莎拉，我以为你应该很高兴 我们不会再拿动物实验
Sarah, I thought you'd be happy. We are giving the animals a break.
进度太快是不对的科学态度 不管谁是那只实验猪
Moving this fast is bad science, no matter who the guinea pig is.
- 我不相信委员会会批准 - 我觉得很酷
I can't believe they approved this. - I think it's fucking cool.
你当然是啦
You would.
如果要走下一步 这就是合理的步骤
If we're to move forward, this is the next logical step.
我隐形三天后再还原
L'll stay shifted for three days and then we'll perform a quantum reversión.
好耶
Fuck, yes.
我能信赖你们吗？
Can I count on your best work?
很好
Good.
我们怎会让他说服我们的？
How did we let him talk us into this?
待会再谈好吗？
Can we talk about it later?
我正想跟你做爱
I'm trying to make love to you.
我们这是拿职业生涯去冒险
We're risking our professional lives here.
是的，麦特，我知道
Yes, Matt, I realize.
那我们为何会同意？
Then why did we agree to it?
因为我们是笨蛋
Because we're suckers.
因为当你到达地图的边缘时...
And because sometimes when you get to the edge of the map...
很想继续航行看看前面到底是什么
...you have to keep sailing to see what's out there.
也许我们都知道赛巴斯辛能成功
And maybe because we both know that Sebastian can pull it off.
- 问你另一个问题 - 是关于谁要在上面吗？
Let me ask another question. - Is it about who's gonna be on top?
你想念跟他在一起吗？
Ever miss being with him?
你干嘛问这个？
Why do you ask that?
因为他的标准太高
Because he sets the bar pretty high.
跟你说个秘密
Let me tell you a little secret.
赛巴斯辛的想法比他本人…
The concept of Sebastian is much more appealing...
…更吸引人
...than Sebastian himself.
而你...
Whereas you...
你系统...
You're methodical...
...精确...
...precise...
...十分小心.
...and very, very thorough.
还有...
And besides...
...和你做舒服多了.
...you fit better.
我们准备好了
We're ready for you.
回头见了
See you later.
- 现在改变主意还来得及 - 我以为我该是最紧张的
It's not too late to stop. - I thought I was the nervous one.
- 我们还有很多需要克服的 - 听过超人和女超人故事吗？
We have a lot riding on this. Hear about Superman and Wonder Woman?
- 正经一点吧 - 这故事超好笑
Stop clowning around. - It's a good one.
超人有天飞过市中心
Superman is flying over Metropolis.
他很饥渴，找遍每个屋顶
He's horny and checking out the rooftops.
他看到女超人在 正义联盟屋顶做日光浴
He sees Wonder Woman sunning on the roof of the Justice League.
她裸身躺著，双脚大张 这不是等人上吗？
She's lying there buck-naked, spread- eagle, wanting to be fucked, right?
超人就对他自己说：
Superman says to himself:
“我一定要上她”
'I gotta get myself some Wonder pussy.'
他想他能飞下去来个闪电攻击…
Then he realizes that he could fly down, do a little fast pumping...
…在她察觉之前就闪人 因为他是超人
...and be gone before she knew, since he's Superman.
他比子弹还快
Faster than a speeding bullet.
超人冲下去，给她闪电一发 而她连他都没看清楚
He swoops down, he fucks her so quick, she doesn't even see him.
女超人坐起来说 “搞什么鬼啊？”
Wonder Woman sits up, says, 'What the fuck was that?'
隐形人就说： 我不知道…
And the Invisible Man says, 'I don't know...
…不过我的屁眼痛毙了
...but my asshole is killing me.'
好笑吧？拜托，很好笑的
That's funny, right? Come on, guys. That's funny.
小姐们，拜托，这是科学
Ladies, please. This is science.
开始静脉注射
Starting IV drip.
- 你感觉如何？ - 有点紧张
Okay, how are you feeling? - I'm a little tense.
脉搏88，血压140/95 有点高
Pulse 88. BP 140l95. It's a bit elevated.
不知为何
I wonder why.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
确定
Positive.
- 上面好了吗？ - 好了
We ready up in heaven? - Ready.
开始录影
Mary's rolling.
希望这不是部惊悚片，开始
I just hope we're not making a snuff film. Rolling.
要是这样，我要他的保时捷
If it is, I got dibs on his Porsche.
珍妮丝，你怎能这样说？
Janice, how can you say that?
抱歉
Sorry.
保时捷是我的
Porsche is mine.
实验对象：男性 38岁，重166磅
Subject male, age 38, weight 166 pounds.
配方液已辐射处理
Serum's irradiated.
- 这最好能成 - 一定会成
This better work. - It will.
- 是吗？ - 想打赌吗？
Oh, yeah? - You wanna bet on it?
我要是赢了，也拿不到赌金 所以算了
If I win, you won't be around to pay off, so, no.
准备好了？
Are you ready?
我自己来 要是出错，你不用负责
L'll do it. So if anything goes wrong, you can't be blamed.
好吧
All right.
有遗言吗？
Any last words?
要是我死了，假装我说过睿智的话
Yeah. If I die, pretend I said something deep and clever.
注射时间18点23分
Injection administered at 1823.
- 有何感觉？ - 还没有
Are you feeling anything? - Nothing so far.
- 生命迹象稳定 - 没有变化
Vitals are stable. - Nothing's happening.
人类DNA可能要等久一点
Human DNA structure may take more time.
- 你检试过，对吗？ - 是的
You pulsed it right? - Yes.
重新检验辐射程序 不可能没反应
Recheck the radiation. It can't be non-reactive.
生物电流活动正常
No change in bioelectric activity.
该死！
Goddamn it!
- 我再将程序重覆一次，好吗？ - 等等
L'll repeat the protocol, okay? - Wait.
我有感觉了
I'm starting to feel something.
我的手…
It's my arm. It's...
它变热了
It's getting warm.
开始有刺痛感
Okay, it's starting to tingle.
刺痛转移到背部
Yeah, it's moving down into my back.
开始了
Here we go.
妈的！好痛
Shit! It hurts.
我快被扯碎了
It's tearing me.
心跳剧增，脉搏110
Heartbeat's elevated. Pulse at 110. 130.
天啊，没想到这么痛
Christ, didn't think it would hurt so much.
法兰科，数据！
Frank, readouts!
脑波活动剧烈 他濒临崩溃
Brain waves are spiking. He's on the verge of a seizure.
脉搏165-170 血压180/110
Pulse is 165, 170. Blood pressure 180 over 110.
赛巴斯辛，你听得见吗？
Sebastian, can you hear me? Sebastian?
- 他心脏会炸开！ - 电击器准备！
His heart'll blow out! - Standby paddles!
来了
Coming in.
读数显示，他快要隐形了
Subcellular quantum. He's shifting.
生物电流读数危险
Bioelectric in the red.
等等
Wait.
他隐形了
He's going.
脉搏180
Pulse is 180.
读数稳定
Holding stable.
天啊
Holy shit.
脉搏下降170，160，150
Pulse is dropping. 170, 160, 150.
18点26分到达隐形状态
Bio-quantum phase-shift occurred at 1826.
他还好吧？
Is he okay?
他受刺激过度，昏过去了
Yeah, he's in bioelectric shock. Passed out from the trauma.
生命迹象回复正常？
Vitals returning to normal?
脉搏110，下降中 血压130/75
Pulse 110, dropping. Blood pressure's 130l75.
- 量子读数正常 - 电流活动稳定
Quantum readings normal. - Electrical activity is stabilizing.
有东西跟后代子孙说了
Something to tell the grandkids.
脉搏稳定在85
Pulse steady at 85.
你成功了，你是第一个
You did it. You're the first.
没事
It's okay. It's okay.
你睡着了
You nodded off.
- 他的呼吸声有催眠作用 - 是的
His breathing's hypnotic. - Yeah.
过了多久了？
How long has it been?
17小时
Seventeen hours.
我们所获得的资料 足供两辈子来研究
And we already have enough data for two lifetimes of research.
欢迎来到美丽新世界，琳
It's a brave new worid, Lin.
我一直看著那个洞 心想他是否真的在那里
I keep looking at that hole, wondering if he's really there.
- 你看到了吗？ - 你听得见吗？
Did you see that? - Sebastian, can you hear me?
天啊！灯光！快把灯关掉！
Christ! The lights! Turn off the goddamn lights!
我无法闭上眼睛
I can't close my eyes.
你可以，但你眼皮变透明了
You can, but your eyelids are transparent.
真怪 我感觉没变，但我却不在了
It's weird. I feel the same, but I'm not here.
你在的
You're here.
我在这里
Sebastian? - I'm right here.
- 哪里？ - 镜子前面
Where? - At the mirror.
看我自己
Looking at myself.
或者，不是看我自己
Or, rather, not looking at myself.
他情况如何？
Hey, how's he doing?
你为何不问赛巴斯辛？
Why don't you ask Sebastian?
- 你有何感觉？ - 就各方面而言，还不算太坏
How do you feel? - Oh, not too bad, considering.
不知道他在哪里
Just wanna set the mood.
灯光的关系，他眼皮是透明的
It's the light. His eyelids are transparent.
变成鬼是什么样子？
So, what's it like being a ghost?
鬼是死的,我是活的.
Ghosts are dead. I'm very much alive.
得了,别发神经.
Come on, don't be a dick.
对不起,我本性使然.
Sorry. I couldn't resist.
好,我感觉我们像是在玩马可波罗游戏.
Okay, now I feel like we're playing Marco Polo.
我想知道他现在在哪?
I wonder where he is now.
看来实验并未改变你的个性
Well, I see the procedure's not changed your personality.
- 他刚掠过我身边 - 别担心，我来找他
He just brushed by me. - No worries, I'm on it.
- 看到什么没有？ - 他在哪？
Do you see anything? - Where is he?
看到他了？
You got him?
Sebastian?
找到了，老大
Got you, chief.
你们真是无趣
You guys have no sense of fun.
我的天啊
Shit. Oh, my God.
我安排随时有人值班待命 以备你有任何需要
L've arranged for one of us to be here 24l7, if you need anything.
在你隐形期间，全员戒备 一有状况，我们会在--
The team's gonna be on alpha-call alert, so we can be here within...
半小时内到，我知道 那程序是我写的，记得吗？
Thirty minutes. I know. I wrote the procedure, remember?
我只是想让你安心 热感应监视摄影机已架好
I was reassuring you. There's a thermal camera for observation.
- 她就喜欢这样，对吧？ - 什么？
She likes this, doesn't she? - What?
- 主导一切 - 是啊，她爱死了
Being in charge. - Oh, yeah. She loves it.
也该是换人发号施令的时候了
It's about time the shoe was on the other foot.
请记住
Well, just remember.
这还是我的计划
It's still my project.
- 你确定你要值大夜？ - 我反正也没社交生活
You okay taking the late shift? - It's not like I have a social life.
我知道，工作狂就是这样
I know. The workaholic's curse.
卡特6点会来换班
Carter's gonna be in by 6 to spell you.
我8点到，有事就通知我
I'm here at 8. Call me if you need to.
我不会有事，回去休息吧
L'll be fine. Get some sleep.
- 好，拜 - 拜
Okay. Bye. - Bye.
Sarah?
你醒着吗？
Are you awake?
赛巴斯辛？
Sebastian?
你在这里吗？
Are you in here?
我知道你在
I know you're in here.
我再看监视器的时候,他回到床上了.
Then when I checked the monitor again, he's back in the bed.
当我问他昨晚做什么了 他说他只是去喝咖啡来.
When I ask him where he'd been, he said he's getting coffee.
- 那你怎么打电话找我? - 因为我不确定,我现在都不确定
Why didn't you call me? - Because I wasn't sure. I'm still not.
我想,我也可能在做梦 但我还是要告诉你们
I mean, I could have been dreaming. I just thought I should tell someone.
那你打算怎么做?
What do you wanna do?
我不知道,我不相信他会做那种下流事
I don't know. I have a tough time believing he'd be that crude.
我觉得我好傻.
I feel so stupid.
那我们为什么不去找他谈? 看他怎么说...
Why don't I talk to him? L'll see what he says...
不,别.
No, don't.
要知道,可能不是真的. 我不该提这个.
You know, it's probably nothing. I shouldn't have mentioned it.
- 第一晚情况如何？ - 睡不着
So how was your first night? - Restless.
闭不上眼睛很难睡着
Hard to sleep without closing your eyes.
你都做些什么？
What'd you do?
起来几次，到处走走
Got up a couple of times. Walked around.
莎拉说你昨晚不在房间里
Sarah mentioned you weren't in your room.
我是去倒杯咖啡喝
I got a cup of coffee.
以后也许你能通知值班者 你去哪里…
In the future, you'll wanna tell the on-call where you're going...
…以免你出了什么事
...just in case something happens to you.
感谢你关心，这不是什么问题
I'm touched by your concern, but it's not a problem.
希望别造成问题
We don't want it to become one.
一切正常
Everything's normal.
把这些拿掉吧
All right, let's get these off.
你还好吧？
You okay?
很好，怎么了？
Yeah. Why?
你似乎有点紧张
You seem a little nervous.
不，我很好
No, I'm fine.
你在看我吗？
Are you looking at me?
没有
No.
为什么？
Why?
没什么
No reason.
- 那个客人怎样？ - 这砘镎疑衔遥他说：
What was the clientele like? - This guy comes up to me and says:
“我喜欢女人跟喜欢咖啡一样” 现在还有人说这种台词？
'I like my women like my coffee.' People still use that line?
- 也许他是说你又冷又苦 - 自以为很好笑
Maybe he meant cold and bitter. - Very funny.
我要去上厕所，别让卡特偷吃
I gotta take a leak. Keep Carter away from my food.
- 我尽量，但我不保证 - 好
L'll try, but I can't promise. - All right.
一开始很怪，但后来就好了
It'd be freaky, but it'd settle down.
如果你是隐形人，你会怎么做？
No, what would you do if you knew you couldn't be seen?
这整件事都让我反感 我没戴热视镜就不敢上厕所
It gives me the creeps. I can't take a piss without wearing my thermals.
- 好像每个人都想看 - 我怎么知道？
Like anyone wants to see that. - How do I know?
你是问我们还是赛巴斯辛的做法？
Are you asking what we'd do or what Sebastian would do?
有何不同？
The difference?
赛巴斯辛的本性和别人的不同
There's human nature, then there's Sebastian.
他老爱说他是上帝
He's always joking that he's God.
想想他要是能为所欲为的话
Imagine what he'd do if left to his own devices.
真可怕的想法
Scary thought.
- 还好，一切都快结束了 - 感谢上帝
Thankfully, it's almost over. - Hallelujah.
这只是开始，你认为赛巴斯辛坏？
It's just beginning. You think Sebastian's bad?
假使是军队用上这技术会如何？
Lmagine if the military gets their hands on this.
最好是我们的军队用就好
Better our military than someone else's.
赛巴斯辛，该死
Sebastian, goddamn it.
你根本不知道这有多好玩 你真该试试
You have no idea how much fun this is. You should try it.
我会有机会的
I'm sure l'll have my chance.
放轻松
Hey, relax.
这是我最后一晚 我想我们可以来个实验
It's my last night, so I thought we'd try one more experiment.
猜猜看这是什么？
Can you guess what this is?
什么？
What?
感觉如何？
How did it feel?
有点太熟悉了
A little too familiar.
想知道跟隐形人做爱的感觉吗？
Wanna know what it's like to make love to an invisible man?
- 它就像以前一样 - 什么意思？
It'd just be like old times. - What do you mean?
老是感觉不到你的存在
You were never there.
我现在就在这里
Well, I'm here now.
我们曾经谈过，记得吗？
We talked about this once, remember?
谈什么？
What?
你想知道有何不同
You wondered if you'd know the difference.
赛巴斯辛，我知道有何不同
Sebastian, I do know the difference.
不是我看不到，是我感觉不到
It's not what I don't see. It's what I don't feel.
休息吧
Get some rest.
明天是个大日子
Got a big day tomorrow.
实验目标：凯恩博士
Subject: Dr. Sebastian Caine.
目前已隐形86小时又23分钟
Currently in phase-shift 86 hours, 23 minutes.
第四级程序 注射凯氏蛋白127号
D-phase protocol. Injecting Serial Protein Caine 127.
辐射程序完成
Irradiation complete.
准备好了
Set.
- 你准备好了吗？ - 还没完全
Are you ready? - Not really.
我才正开始享受呢
I was starting to enjoy myself.
真可惜
Well, tough.
一分钟后见
We'll see you in a minute, my friend.
注射时间早上9点28分
Injection occurred at 0928.
你有什么感觉？
What are you feeling?
情况不对
Something's not right.
心跳增高，法兰克
Heartbeat elevated. Frank.
隐形读数不规则
Shift indicators are erratic.
- 生物电流量跳动 - 检查辐射量，电击器
Bioelectric's jumping. - Check radiation. Crash cart.
怎么回事？
What?
发生什么事？
What's happening?
我无法呼吸
I can't breathe.
- 检查气管 - 他停止呼吸了，快插管
Check his airway. - His lungs are seized. Intubate.
卡特！
Carter!
快插管！
Tube him!
Sebastian.
- 他正要进入转换阶段 - 把他搬上台
He's going into phase-shift. - Get him on the table.
没讯号了
We lost our signals.
该死！
Goddamn!
- 准备静脉注射 - 我在弄
Get me an IV of AG-7. - I'm on it.
没有脉搏
No pulse.
我量不到脉搏！
L've got no pulse!
开始做CPR
Starting CPR.
不准你死
Don't you die on me.
- 我不准你死 - 量到脉搏了
Don't you fucking die on me. - I'm getting a pulse.
- 赛巴斯辛，你听得见吗？ - 我想他休克了
Sebastian, can you hear me? - He's going into shock.
天啊
Jesus.
Hi.
我想我们失败了
So I guess it didn't work.
对
No.
你看来很担心，一定很糟糕
You look worried. Must've been bad.
你差点死掉
You almost died.
置之于死地而后生嘛
Whatever doesn't kill me makes me stronger.
是啊，然后我们的前途完了 要怎么跟克拉玛说呢？
Yeah, and ends our careers. What are we gonna tell Kramer?
不用说
Nothing.
他还不需要知道
He doesn't need to know yet.
- 不能继续骗其他人了 - 我们别无选择
We can't keep lying to the others. - We don't have a choice.
要是我继续像这样…
If I'm gonna be stuck like this for a while...
…我们就得做些调整
...we'll have to make a few adjustments.
好了
Done.
- 打开 - 这儿
Open. - Here.
好，抬头
Okay, lift.
卡特，拿风扇来
Carter, get the fan.
好，别动
Okay, don't move.
别动
Don't move.
谢谢，这样好多了
Thanks. That's better.
拿去
Here you go.
- 这算是一大改进 - 你看来很像人了
It's an improvement. - You'd almost pass for human.
- 他以前就不像 - 至少你们可以跟一张脸说话了
He couldn't before. - You have a face you can talk to now.
也可以在普通灯光下工作
We can all work in normal light again.
让我们看看我们是否无法 找出问题的症结
Let's see if we can't try to figure out what went wrong.
而且在他开始咬人以前
Before he starts biting people too.
“不稳定”
- 该死！ - 什么？
Goddamn it! - What?
又无法凝聚
I lost cohesión again.
- 快完成了吗？ - 不
Are you any closer? - No.
我就是找不出B和C
You know, I can't figure out the B and C of it.
B和C？
The B and C?
小学五年级老师跟我说 天才能从A就到D…
My 5th grade teacher told me that genius is getting from A to D...
…不需要经过B和C
...without having to go through B and C.
赛巴斯辛就行
Sebastian can do that.
但我就需要找到B和C
But me, I gotta have the B and C.
等等，赛巴斯辛，就快好了
Hold on, Sebastian. We're almost there.
快点，快让开！
Come on, guys. Out of the way!
我无法再撑下去了
I can't take much more testing.
我了解这有多不好过
I know how hard it is.
鬼扯，你什么都不了解
Bullshit. You don't know anything.
我们都不好过
This isn't easy for any of us.
去你的，麦特！你才好过呢
Fuck you, Matt! It is easy for you.
我应该只有隐形三天
I was to be in phase-shift for three days.
已经十天了，知道吗？！
It's been 10 fucking days, all right?!
十天的组织实验 辐射实验和那些鬼针头！
Ten days of tissue tests, radiation tests and your fucking needles!
我再也受不了了
I can't fucking take it anymore.
- 我是说--  - 去你的！
What I meant was... - Fuck what you meant!
你别想--
And don't ever...
你别想跟我说你有多不好受
Don't ever tell me how hard you have it.
好了,赛巴斯辛, 你累了需要休息.
Come on, Sebastian, you're tired and you need to rest.
我不愿在这里再熬一晚上.
I can't believe I gotta spend another night in this place.
我们正在尽全力解决.
We're trying to do everything we can.
是,但还不够.
Yeah, that's not enough.
辣妹来了
There she is.
我要吸吮你的乳头
L'd suck the tits right off of you.
凯恩博士，有事吗？
Hey. Dr. Caine, what's going on?
我是来告诉你，我要出去一下
Just stopped by to let you know I'm going out for a while.
等等，出去？ 等一等，凯恩博士
Wait. Going out? Hold it a second. Dr. Caine.
Sebastian.
凯恩博士
Dr. Caine.
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我再不出去就要发疯了
If I don't get out, l'll go nuts.
- 但你不可以离开这建筑 - 为什么？
You can't leave the compound. - Why not?
- 这是规定 - 那是我规定的，我刚改了
It's the rule. - It's my rule, I just changed it.
- 授权码 - 凯恩0027
Authorization. - Caine 0027.
- 确认 - 你不能就这样更改规定
Confirmed. - You can't just change it.
我不能在这垃圾堆呆一辈子！
I'm not gonna spend my life in this godforsaken dump!
我要出去！几小时就回来！
I'm going out! Be back in a couple of hours!
该死！
Oh, shit!
- 喂？ - 我是卡特，出乱子了
Hello? - It's Carter. We got a problem.
- 你好吗？艾德 - 嗨，博士
How's it going, Ed? - Hey, doc.
- 好久不见了 - 你知道我就是这样
I haven't seen you in a while. - You know how it is sometimes.
忙著工作
Work, work, work.
我已经开始担心 你的车子都没动过
I was beginning to worry because your car hadn't moved.
谢了，艾德
Thanks a lot, Ed.
但一切都很好
But everything's cool.
你看、你看
Hey, look. Look.
- 你看他 - 他好怪
Look at that. - Man, he's weird.
- 天啊 - 妈咪！妈咪！
Oh, my God. - Mommy! Mommy!
- 妈咪！妈咪！ - 怎么了？
Mommy! Mommy! - What?
- 怎么了？ - 你看，有鬼
What? - Look, it's a ghost.
- 别傻了 - 妈，真的是鬼
Don't be ridiculous. - Mom, it's a ghost.
实验室见，我去他家看看
L'll meet you at the lab. L'll go by his place just in case.
实验室见
L'll see you there.
他可能在这里
He could be here.
可能在任何地方
He could be anywhere.
妈的
Shit.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
谁会知道呢？
Who's gonna know?
赛巴斯辛?
Sebastian?
该死
Oh, shit.
麦特，是我，他回来过
Matt, it's me. He was here.
不，他把头套拿掉了
No, he took his mask off.
他一定在外面 我不知道他去哪了
He must be outside somewhere. I don't know where he went.
我要回实验室了
I'm coming back to the lab.
怎么找？怎么去找？ 我根本看不见他
How? How am I supposed to do that? I can't fucking see him.
你说你要我们对他开枪？ 我参一脚
You say you want us to shoot him? I'm in.
他是凯恩博士，不是猴子 我们反应过度了吧？
It's not a monkey, it's Dr. Caine. Aren't we overreacting here?
我才不管，他对外面有危险性
I don't give a rat's ass if we are. Out there, he's at risk.
要是他被人发现，计划就完了
If someone finds out what he is, the whole program is destroyed.
别紧张，没有人会发现的
Jeez, relax. Nobody's gonna find out.
- 我还可以射他吗？ - 你去哪了？
Can I still shoot him? - Where have you been?
我跟卡特说了
I told Carter.
我快疯了，我回家拿点东西
I was getting stir-crazy. I went home to pick up stuff.
鬼扯
Bullshit.
我去过你家
I went to your apartment.
你不只是拿点东西
You did more than 'pick up stuff.'
- 你在说些什么？ - 你怎能这样？
What are you talking about? - You, of all people. How could you?
你在我家看到了什么？
What did you see in my apartment?
你的脸、衣服
I saw your face, your clothes.
你为何要到外面去？
Sebastian, in public. Why'd you have to go out in public?
我还是计划领导人 我有决定权
I'm still project leader. It's my decisión to make.
没错，你有决定权
You're right. It's your decisión.
但你要是再离开，我发誓 我一定直接报告委员会
But if you leave again, I swear l'll go straight to the committee.
拿你的生涯冒险？
Throw your career away?
不像吧
Not likely.
试试看吧
Try me.
就这样？
So that's it, huh?
我成了真正的白老鼠
I'm officially a fucking lab rat.
你自愿的，你早知到后果
You volunteered. You knew the consequences.
下回清点存货时 弄个转轮给我跑吧
Next time you do inventory, get me an exercise wheel.
是，当然
Yeah, sure.
大家收拾好，回家吧
Let's pack it up and go home.
- 转轮？他真的想要？ - 你想呢？
Exercise wheel? Was he serious? - What do you think?
委员会知道我们在做什么吧？
The committee knows what we've done, don't they?
- 该死，琳！ - 把他还原就没关系了
Shit, Lin! - Won't matter if we can get him back.
- 我不相信你那么做！ - 你有否认的权利，因你不知道
I can't believe you did that! - You have deniability, you didn't know.
我只求你别背叛我们
All I ask is please, please don't fuck us.
- 她会说出去吗？ - 不，她涉入太深了
Think she'll say anything? - No, she's in too far.
- 我不担心她 - 赛巴斯辛
She doesn't worry me. - Sebastian.
他比动物们隐形的更久 那可能影响他的神智
He's been gone longer than the animals. It might affect his mind.
万一他神智已经起变化了呢？
What if it already has?
别动
Hold still.
很好
Good.
- 那是什么感觉？ - 什么意思？
So, what was it like? - What do you mean?
- 你到外面世界去的时候 - 我只是到处走走而已
When you were out in the worid. - I just walked around. You know.
你只是到处走走而已 拜托，还有别的吧？
You just walked around. Come on, there's more, right?
比方说呢？
Like what?
要是我…
Man, if it was me...
…我会开人的玩笑、恶作剧
...l'd be fucking with people, whispering in ears.
到内衣店逛，我会为所欲为
L'd be hanging out at Victoria's Secret. L'd be the king.
太孩子气了吧？
Childish, don't you think?
不
No.
那时很晚，我又没出去多久
Well, it was late. I wasn't out for very long.
你有去找人吗？
Did you see anybody?
有一个女孩
There was this one girl.
- 你没戏弄她？ - 没有
Did you mess with her? - No.
也许我有点吓到她了
Well, maybe I scared her a little. - Yeah?
那感觉如何？
How'd that feel?
我喜欢
I liked it.
真不错
Nice.
琳，记得B和C吗？ 我想我找到了
Hello. - Lin. Remember the B and C? I think I found it.
目前最佳达成百分之55还原
55 percent reversión. That's the best we've gotten yet.
蛋白质结构没进展 重点是辐射量的掌握
Protein structure was a dead end. Key was to manipulate radiation signature.
百分之75、80
75 percent. 80 percent.
- 快
82. - Come on.
成功了
We've got it.
不，变慢了
No, it's slowing.
- 乐观点 - 是变慢了
Be an optimist. - It's slowing down.
88、百分之92
88. 92 percent.
百分之93
93 percent.
百分之94
94 percent.
百分之95
95 percent.
- 不！ - 该死！
No! - Shit!
- 细胞链溃决 - 还原程度只达百分之95
Cellular bonds are collapsing. - Full quantum cascade at 95 percent.
了不起的突破
Some breakthrough.
要是我现此接受试验 那我早就挂了
If I were on a table right now, l'd be a steaming pile of flesh.
别引诱我
Don't tempt me.
很接近了，这很重要
We're closer, which counts.
接近！他刚以量子能量换取稳定？
Closer! He just traded quantum energy for stability!
- 太可笑了 - 拜托
It's ludicrous. - Come on.
- 你火大是因为你没想到 - 是吗，麦特？
You're pissed you didn't think of it. - Really?
百分之95？浪费我的时间！
95 percent? That's not even worth my time! For Christ sake.
混蛋
Asshole.
至少我们有希望了.
At least now we have some hope.
什么?
What?
你这白痴，你是怎么回事？
You're a fucking moron. What is your problem?
麦特有发现，他需要你帮忙
Matt is onto something and he could use your help.
是啊，他有发现
Yeah, he's onto something, all right.
他多年来只会跟我屁股后分食
He's on my coattails. He's been riding them for years.
少自大了，他拼命要帮你
Get off your fucking pedestal. He's trying like hell to fix you.
是杀我吧
Or kill me.
知道最糟糕的是什么吗？
And you know what the sad part is?
我有才能，却无法运用
I have this gift and I can't even use it.
现在成了才能了
So now it's a gift.
没错，就是才能
Damn right it's a gift.
如果你不短视 你就该让我出去探索它的
If you weren't so shortsighted, you'd let me out of this cage to explore it.
如果你不那么的短视 你该跟我们一起救你自己
If you weren't so shortsighted, you'd be with us trying to save your life.
救我？
My life?
我身陷牢笼
I have no fucking life.
我是个囚犯
I'm a prisoner.
- 不，你不是囚犯 - 是吗？
No, you're not a prisoner. - Oh, yeah?
你在今晚离开时，会这么想吗？
Is that what you think when you leave here at night?
你就是当我身陷这个牢笼…
Is that how you alleviate your guilt...
…你却在家跟你男友上床…
...when I'm stuck in this shithole and you're at home...
…来减轻罪恶感的吗？
...fucking your boyfriend?
你最烦恼什么？
What bothers you most?
你身陷牢笼…
That you don't have a life...
…而我没有？
...or that I do?
法兰克，我要去实验室
Frank, I'm coming down to the lab.
你不睡吗？
Don't you sleep?
- 天才从不睡觉 - 好，需要我就叫一声
Da Vinci never slept. - Okay. I'm here if you need me.
我认识维金尼欧
不，不，不
No, no, no, no.
Hello.
混球…
Motherfucker...
再晚一点，我就自己先玩了
If you were any later, I would have started without you.
天啊！
Jesus!
我没看到有人
I don't see anything.
喂？
Hello?
没有
No.
没有，他在
No, he's here.
我确定，我正看著他
Yes, I'm sure. I'm staring at him.
有事吗？
Is something wrong?
- 要我叫醒他吗？ - 不了，我只是问问
You want me to wake him? - No, I was just checking.
她以为她是谁？
Who the fuck does she think she is?
我不够好？不够好？
I'm not good enough for her? I'm not good enough?
就让他们俩看我有多行
L'll show them both how good I am.
安静！
Quiet!
想跟我玩吗，婊子？
You wanna fuck with me, bitch?
知道玩弄我的下场吗？！
You know what happens when you fuck with me?!
别担心，没人会伤害你的
Don't worry. Nobody's gonna hurt you. No one.
- 你今天看上去气色很好 - 是的.
My, you're looking spry this morning. - Oh, yeah.
没有比只看别人睡觉...
There's nothing more stimulating than staying up...
...自己不睡更刺激的了.
...watching someone else sleep.
早上好,甘.
Good morning, gang.
早上好.
Good morning.
你好,马吉,早上好,吉里斯.
Hi, Maggie. Good morning, giris.
赛巴斯辛...
Sebastian...
...你醒了?
...you awake?
现在醒了.
I am now.
昨晚注意到什么动静了吗?
Notice anything unusual last night?
没有,怎么了?
Nope, nothing at all. Why?
富兰克林3号,他死了.
Franklin 3, he's dead.
怎样?
So?
所以我想你可能会听到什么.
So I thought maybe you heard something.
- 我在睡觉. - 整晚?
I was asleep. - Yeah, all night?
你是在怀疑我还是..?
Are you accusing me of something?
不是,只是这不正常,不是么?, 一条狗无缘死去?
No, it just doesn't make sense, does it, a dog dying just like that?
听着,我知道你对它们有感情, 莎拉.动物都会死亡的.
Look, I know how you feel about them, Sarah, but animals do die.
这是无法改变的事实.
It's simply a fact of life.
这是昨晚的.
That's all night.
- 这样他从来没离开过屋子? - 我想是的.
So he never left the room? - Yeah, I guess.
我不知道 他为什么要杀死一条狗呢?
I don't know. Why would he kill a dog, right?
什么人?
Hello?
赛巴斯辛?
Sebastian?
赛巴斯辛, 这并不好玩.
Sebastian, this is not funny.
- 你在这里干什么? - 他呢?
What are you doing here? - Where is he?
他在睡觉,怎么了?
He's asleep, why?
我马上就来.
L'll be right back.
赛巴斯辛?
Sebastian?
马特,启动阿尔法呼叫. 我要求所有人都来
Matt, activate alpha call. I want everyone in here now.
- 加班? - 挣钱不容易啊.
Working late? - That's what they pay us for.
真聪明 一直让它重覆播放相同影像
It's really pretty clever. All it does is loop the same image.
怎么办？把他抓起来？
What do we do now? Go after him?
不，我们向委员会报告
No. We're going to the committee.
我们该跟他谈谈吧？
Shouldn't we wait and talk to him?
他空手杀了一只狗
He killed a dog with his bare hands.
- 你亲眼看到了？ - 他每晚都出去…
You were there? - He went out every night...
…完全忽视他自己 和我们的安全
...with absolute disregard for his safety and ours.
- 他做了什么？ - 我不想知道
What's he done? - I don't wanna think about it.
- 情况多严重？ - 你们没有误导委员会
Are we in trouble? - You didn't mislead the committee.
我们会负全责
We'll take responsibility.
- 他回来，我们该怎么办？ - 什么都不用做
What do we do when he comes back? - Nothing.
等委员会派守卫来
The committee will bring security.
我们明早向你们简报
We'll brief you tomorrow morning.
- 许可. - 麦凯 1-德尔他-835.
Authorization, please. - McKay 1-Delta-835.
- 你确信你要这么做? - 这是正确的.
You sure about this? - It's the right thing to do.
从吉文 赛巴斯辛的过去看, 他的行径并不让我惊讶.
Given Sebastian's history, this behavior doesn't surprise me.
你应说点什么.
You should've said something.
我信任你们，以为你们能处理
I had a lot of faith in you, thinking you'd take care of this.
我知道，我们这么做错了
I know what we did was wrong.
错了，不足以形容此事的严重
Wrong doesn't even begin to describe it.
先别谈这个
Let's leave it here.
我现在通知凯瑟将军紧急开会
L'll call General Caster and convene the committee.
回实验室吧，赛巴斯辛由我们处理
You go back to the lab. We'll handle him.
我们还能做些什么？
Is there anything we can do?
准备打包回家吧
You might think about clearing out your offices.
付了那么大的代价 我们很抱歉
For what it's worth, we're both very sorry.
现在道歉有点迟了
A little late for apologies.
霍华？
Howard?
怎么回事？
What was that about?
- 工作上出了点事 - 多严重？
Just a screwup at work. - How bad?
得叫醒几个将军了
Bad enough to wake a few generals.
老板好
Hi, boss.
Martha!
救命！
Help!
Martha!
救命！救命！
Howard? - Help! Help!
霍华！
Howard!
- 干嘛这么紧张？ - 你吓到我了
Why so jumpy? - You just surprised me.
不跟我道早安？
No 'good morning' for me today?
你不爱我了
You don't love me anymore.
- 只是有点赶 - 没关系
Just in a hurry. - Well, that's okay.
今天将会很忙的
It's gonna be a busy day.
他何时回来的？
When did he get back?
凌晨3点 整晚就一直在实验室晃
Three a.m. He's been wandering around the lab ever since.
克拉玛来电了吗？
Kramer called yet?
也许他还在跟委员会开会
He's probably still meeting with the committee.
也该有消息了，我打给他
We should have heard something. I'm calling.
喂，克拉玛博士在吗？
Hello, is Dr. Kramer there?
什么？
What?
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 怎么了？ - 他死了
What's wrong? - He's dead.
- 什么？ - 他昨晚溺毙在游泳池
What? - He drowned in his pool last night.
请接凯瑟将军
General Caster, please.
Hello. Hello?
电话没声音
There's no dial tone.
- 这里也不能打外线 - 最好上去通知警卫
There's no outside line here either. - We'd better alert security.
- 授权码 - 麦凯1D835
Authorization, please. - McKay 1-Delta-835.
授权码无效，拒绝请求
Authorization invalid. Request denied.
这倒新鲜，麦凯1D835
That's a first. McKay 1-Delta-835.
授权码无效，拒绝请求
Authorization invalid. Request denied.
试试我的
Let me try mine.
坎辛顿2R159
Kensington 2-Romeo-159.
授权码无效，拒绝请求
Authorization invalid. Request denied.
出状况了
We've got a problem.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
- 要多久才会有人来找我们？ - 有可能要好几天
When will they start looking for us? - It could take a couple of days.
- 你能侵入安全系统吗？ - 早进去了
Can you hack into the system? - Already in.
- 真烂的系统 - 是因为他太棒了
Some security system. - It's just he's extraordinary.
看来有人比我更棒
Someone's more extraordinary than me.
- 怎么了？ - 系统没问题
What is it? - The system's fine.
我们的密码被更动了 只有一个没动
Our access codes have been removed. There's only one left.
“凯恩赛巴斯辛”
- 我们被困住了？ - 我们去抓他
So we're trapped? - We'll get him.
给我一支
Let me have one.
Sebastian?
他不在这里
He's not in here.
赛巴斯辛，一切都结束了 告诉我们你在哪里？
Okay, Sebastian, fun's over. Tell us where you are.
抱歉，琳达，我不能让你逮捕我
Sorry, Linda, but I can't let you turn me in.
赛巴斯辛，你在哪里？
Sebastian, where are you?
你不知道这种感觉
You have no idea what it's like.
这种力量、自由，我放不掉
The power of it, the freedom. I can't let that go.
不管你怎么做 电话、电梯…
Whatever you're planning, the phones, the elevator...
…都不会有用，他们知道你了
...it's not gonna work. They know about you.
不，他们不知道
No, they don't.
克拉玛没来得及说就挂了
Kramer died before he could tell a soul.
我很确定
I saw to that.
天啊
Jesus.
- 你知道你说了什么吗？ - 一切真是太棒了…
You realize what you're saying? - It's amazing what you can do...
…当你来无影去无踪时
... when you don't have to look at yourself in the mirror anymore.
- 赛巴斯辛 - 再见了，琳达
Sebastian. - Goodbye, Linda.
Sebastian!
该死！
Shit!
珍妮丝呢？
Where's Janice?
她本来跟在后面的
She was right behind us.
糟糕
Oh, fuck.
该死，天啊！
Oh, fuck. Oh, my God!
Janice? Janice!
Janice?
在里面
In there.
- 镇静镖 - 是赛巴斯辛吗？
Darts. - Is it Sebastian?
天啊
Oh, my God.
该死！
Shit!
天啊
Oh, my God.
她本来在后面
She was right behind us.
他怎么能这么做？
How could he do this?
他疯了，真的疯了
He snapped. He fucking snapped.
更糟
It's worse.
- 他计划好的 - 你说什么？
He's thought this through. - What?
他知道我们要逮捕他
He knew we were gonna turn him in.
他知道他的生涯完了…
He knew that his career would be over and his only way out...
…唯一的办法 就是别让人知道他做了什么
...is to make sure no one knows what he is or what he's done.
- 那他得封我们的口 - 真该死！
Which means he'll get rid of us. - Goddamn you!
- 你本可以阻止一切的！ - 冷静点
You could've stopped this! - Back off.
- 你害惨了我们！ - 闭嘴！
You risked our lives! - Shut up!
别叫她闭嘴！她说的对！
Don't tell her to shut up! She's right!
我才不管她对不对！ 我也不管这是谁的错！
I don't care if she's right! I don't care whose fault this is!
我只想知道现在该怎么办？
I just wanna know, what do we do now?
法兰克，你能回复密码吗？
Frank, can you restore the codes?
- 我尽力 - 我们不能坐以待毙
L'll try. - We can't afford to sit here and wait.
没错，我们要去逮住他
We are not gonna wait. We are gonna take him down.
你用过它吗？
Ever use this thing before?
一开始我们想用它来逮隐形鼠
We designed it to help find the rats we kept dropping.
老鼠太小找不到
Too small for thermal scans.
- 接好了 - 开动了
Connecting. - Powering up.
启动移动侦测器
Activating motion detectors.
有动静了
We've got movement.
- 六号通道 - 他在那里
Corridor six. - There he is.
好了
Got it.
- 测试 - 测试
Check. - Check.
- 麦特，小心点 - 帮我们留意四周
Matt, be careful. - Just watch our backs.
- 准备好了？ - 走吧
Ready? - Let's do it.
下个走廊左转
Take a left at the next corridor.
我们能在八号走廊包抄他吗？
Could we trap him in corridor eight?
- 如果他方向不变的话 - 我到五号走廊
lf he keeps heading that way. - I'm on five.
- 有进展吗？ - 我想我们可以爬出去
Anything? - I think we can climb out.
电梯通道里有梯子
There's a ladder in the elevator shaft.
糟糕，我找不到他了
Shit, I lost him.
- 我找不到他了 - 他停止移动了
I lost him. - He stopped moving.
是我、是我
It's me. It's me.
- 找到什么了吗？ - 没有
You have anything? - No, nothing.
他怎么闪掉我们的？
How did he get by us?
不可能
He couldn't have.
Sebastian!
那里，管子后面
There. Behind the pipes.
凯恩博士？
Dr. Caine?
- 听的到我吗？ - 我去逮他
Can you hear me? - I'm taking him down.
掩护我
Cover me.
好了
Covered.
只是个排气口 只是个该死的排气口
It's just a vent. It's just a goddamn vent.
放开他！快放开他！
Let him go! Let him fucking go!
麦特，怎么了？
Matt, what's happening?
卡特受伤了！很严重！
Carter's down! He's hurt bad!
快离开
Get out of there.
赛巴斯辛在哪里？！
Where the fuck is Sebastian?!
该死，他在你上面！
Shit. He's right on top of you!
- 他往哪去？！ - 他往实验室来了
Where's he headed?! - He's coming this way, to the lab.
门在慢慢关起来！ 他把我关起来了！
The doors are closing! He's shutting me in!
- 你找到他了？ - 找到了
You have him? - I do.
他还在那里，就在你那边
He's still there. He's on your side of the door.
- 哪里？ - 就在你前面
Where? - He's right in front of you.
他冲向你了！
He's coming at you!
这里都是热源，有五、六个
I got thermals all over the place. Five or six.
我看不清楚了！
I'm losing resolution!
他在放出热气 你看不到他的
He's pumping out heat. You won't be able to see him.
气温跟他的体温一样
The air's the same temperature as his body.
- 他被困住了 - 我去
He's trapped. - I'm going.
- 那不安全 - 去救卡特！实验室见
It's not safe. - Get Carter! Meet at the lab.
- 我们不该分开！ - 去救卡特
We shouldn't separate! - Get Carter.
我在这儿
Marco. Polo.
你失手了
You missed.
- 现在该你还赌债了 - 来啊！你以为你能打败我吗？！
Now'd be a good time to pay that tab. - Come on! You think you can take me?!
来啊！
Come on!
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
是血浆还是权力把你搞疯了？
Was it the serum that fucked you up, or the power?
你才疯了吧？！ 拾我牙慧…
Aren't you the fucked up one?! Dining on my leftovers...
…只会模仿我！
...no life except the one you borrowed from me!
- 连琳达都是 - 她甩了你，记得吗？
Even with Linda. - She left you, remember?
天啊，她怎会喜欢你这窝囊废！
Jesus Christ, I can't imagine what the fuck she sees in a loser like you!
因为我不是一个混蛋神经病！
I'm not a deranged asshole!
对，但你太软弱！
No, but you're weak!
我以为杀你会很难！ 但我有点喜欢这样
I thought killing you would be hard! But I kind of like it.
我的天啊！ 他的脉搏很弱！呼吸很浅！
Oh, my God. Fuck! His pulse is weak! His breathing's shallow!
- 他没事的！ - 不，他伤的很重！
He'll be okay! - No, it's severe!
- 他不会死的！ - 蹲下来！
He's gonna be okay! - Get down here!
用力压住直到我回来！
Keep applying pressure until I get back!
- 你要去哪？ - 他需要输血
Where you going? - He needs blood.
- 等其他人来！ - 再等他就死定了！
Wait for the others! - Lf I wait, he'll die!
该死！
Sarah! Fuck!
Sebastian?
Sarah?
天，我叫他们在这会合的
God, I told them to meet us here.
Frank?
天啊
Oh, God.
来啊，赛巴斯辛，再向前一步
Come on. Give me one step, Sebastian. One fucking step.
走啊！
Move!
该死
Fuck.
真是一团糟
Hey. Quite a mess.
去你的！
Fuck! You motherfuck...
住手！
Get off!
- 上次我们还很契合啊 - 不，求你不要
We had so much fun the last time. - No, please don't. Please.
祝你好梦
Sweet dreams.
你知道…
You know...
…我一直都很欣赏你的忠心
...l've always admired your feistiness.
该死，卡特！别死！
Goddamn it, Carter! Don't die on me now!
莎拉，他快死了！
Sarah, I'm losing him! Sarah! - Frank.
- 她在哪？ - 他需要输血
Where is she? - He needed blood.
- 她一个人去的？ - 他会死的！
She went alone? - He would've died!
他死了
He's dead.
快点
Come on.
等等
Wait.
Sarah?
继续喷
Matt. - Keep spraying.
老天
Oh, no.
死了
Nothing.
怎么回事？
What's happening?!
她死了对吧？妈的！
She's dead, isn't she? Motherfucker!
Frank!
天啊
Jesus.
我来
I got it. I got it.
天啊！
Oh, God!
- 该死 - 拜拜，琳达
Bye-bye, Linda.
祝你们愉快
Have fun with your boyfriend.
我们被锁住了
We're locked in.
很糟吗？
How bad?
你在失血，但他没伤到器官
- 法兰克呢？ - 死了
You're losing blood, but he didn't hit any organs.
Frank? - No.
我得找东西封住伤口
I gotta find something to close the wound.
该死
Shit.
跟我说话
Talk to me.
我头晕
Everything is spinning.
- 你还清醒吗？ - 我没感觉了
Are you still with me? - I can't feel anything.
感觉的到这个吗？
Can you feel this?
一点点
A little.
别死
Come on.
我要你撑下去
I need you to fight this.
- 我要你保持清醒 - 我尽力
I need you to stay awake. - I'm trying.
拜托，跟我说话
Come on. Talk to me.
跟我说话！
Talk to me!
Matt. Matt! Matt!
你好，我的脸
Hello, face.
我们不会死在这里
We are not gonna die in here.
“硫酸”
我会找人救你的，我答应你
L'll be back with help. I promise.
- 授权码 - 凯恩0027
Authorization, please. - Caine 0027.
- 确认 - 谢谢
Confirmed. - Thank you.
Sebastian!
- 你不准走 - 抱歉，你别无选择
I can't let you leave. - Sorry, you don't have a choice.
我有
Oh, yes, I do.
你以为你是上帝？去见他吧！
You think you're God? L'll show you God!
Shit!
我一直都知道你是个贱货！
I always knew you were a bitch!
贱货！
Bitch!
怪不得我们会分开！
No wonder it didn't work out between us!
离她远点！
Stay the fuck away from her!
我就知道我也能救你一命
Thought l'd save you for a change.
来吧，我听见有爆炸声！
Come on. I heard an explosión!
- 别碰！ - 什么？
Don't touch it! - What?
- 那是硝化甘油 - 我们得停下它
It's nitro. - We gotta stop it.
不行的！快走！
No, we can't! Come on!
电梯里有梯子
There's a ladder in the elevator.
- 你能爬吗？ - 我有选择吗？
Can you climb? - Do I have a choice?
你先爬
You go first.
快爬！
Move!
该死
Oh, shit.
躲到旁边！
Stick to the side!
它掉下来了！
Lt's coming back down!
下去！快下去！
Down! Go down!
天啊
Holy shit.
在它滑下前   ，我们得快点离开
We better go before it slips.
Matt!
放开我！放开我！
Get off of me! Get off of me!
Matt.
- 放开我！ - 最后一吻
Let go of me! - One last kiss.
纪念往日情谊
For old times' sake.
去死吧
Go to hell.
快
Come on.
天啊
Oh, my God.
不要天了，什么都不要了
Not God. Not anymore.